<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An act for the inlargement of the periods of time limited in an act for the better execution of His Majesties gracious declaration for the settlement of His kingdom of Ireland, &amp;c.</title>
            <title>Public General Acts. 1662. 14 Charles II c.2.</title>
            <author>Ireland.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1662</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A45982</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing I316A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R216255</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99827995</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99827995</idno>
            <idno type="VID">32421</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A45982)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 32421)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1911:5)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An act for the inlargement of the periods of time limited in an act for the better execution of His Majesties gracious declaration for the settlement of His kingdom of Ireland, &amp;c.</title>
                  <title>Public General Acts. 1662. 14 Charles II c.2.</title>
                  <author>Ireland.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by John Crook, printer to the Kings most excellent Majesty, and are to be sold by Sam. Dancer,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1662.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Ireland --  History --  1660-1688 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  Politics and government --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:32421:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 19 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:32421:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 19 -->
            <p>AN ACT FOR THE INLARGEMENT OF THE Periods of Time, LIMITED In an ACT for the better Execution of His Majeſties Gracious Declaration for the Set<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlement of His KINGDOM of <hi>Ireland,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>C R
HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE
DIEV ET MON DROIT</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>D<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>BLIN:</hi> Printed by <hi>John Crook,</hi> Printer to the KINGS moſt Excellent MAJESTY, and are to be ſold by <hi>Sam. Dancer,</hi> 1662.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="act">
            <pb facs="tcp:32421:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 20 -->
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:32421:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 20 -->
            <head>AN ACT For the Inlargement of the Periods of Time. Limited in an Act for the better execution of his Majeſties graci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Declaration for the Settlement of his Kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas in an Act made this preſent Parliament, intitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, <hi>An Act For the better Execution of his Majeſties Gracious Declaration for the Settlement of his Kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> and ſatisfaction of the ſeveral intereſts of Adventurers, Souldiers, and others his Majeſties Subjects there,</hi> ſeveral Periods of time are appointed and li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mited for the proceeding upon, determining and ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling of the Intereſts of ſun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dry Perſons who are provided for by the ſaid Act, and for the payment of ſuch Sums of Moneys as are to be paid unto His Maieſtie, or others by His appointment; and for that by reaſon of the retarding of the Execution of the ſaid Act, by ſome emergent occaſions which have in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tervened, it may ſo fall out, that the times ſo appointed by the ſaid Act, may not be long enough for the due and or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derly performance and determination of thoſe things, for which by the ſaid Act they were limited, and thereby much preiudice may ariſe to ſeveral perſons and intereſts therein concerned; Be it therefore Enacted by the Kings moſt excel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent Maieſtie, by and with the advice and conſent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons in this preſent Parliament aſſembled, and by the Authority of the ſame, that the Lord Lieutenant, or other Chief Governor or Governors of this Kingdom, and ſix or more of the Council for the time
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:32421:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 21 -->
being, as occaſion ſhall require, may by Act or Acts of Council from time to time to be made, inlarge all or any of the ſaid ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Periods of time in and by the ſaid Act appointed, ſo far as they in their wiſdoms ſhall finde neceſſary. Provided, That none of the ſaid Periods of time be ſo inlarged beyond the ſpace of twelve moneths in the whole, next enſuing from and after the ſeveral and reſpective times whereunto by the ſaid Act they are limited. And forasmuch as there is not any time limited for the Determining and ſettling of ſome other par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticulars mentioned in the ſaid Act, which may very much ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruct the Settlement intended; Be it therefore Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Lord Lieutenant, or other Chief Governor or Governors of this Kingdom and Council as aforeſaid, may by Act or Acts of Council from time to time to be made, limit and appoint ſuch Period or Periods of time for the adiudging, determining and ſettling of the Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lifications of innocent Proteſtants and Papiſts, and the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prizing of ſuch perſons as ſhall be removed thereupon, as they in their iudgements ſhall think fit; ſo as the ſaid Period or Periods of time ſo limited, do not exceed the ſpace of twelve moneths next, after the firſt ſitting of the Commiſſioners ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed for the putting of the ſaid Act in execution, upon the execution of the ſaid Act. And it is by the Authority aforeſaid further Enacted and Declared, That the Period or Periods of time which ſhall be limited, and the ſaid Periods of time which ſhall be inlarged by virtue of this Act, in ſuch manner as aforeſaid, ſhall be as good and effectual to all intents and purpoſes, as if the ſame had been particularly inſerted into, and appointed by the ſaid Act, any thing in the ſaid Act con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained to the contrary notwithſtanding. And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That no Letters Patents paſſed under the Great Seal of <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Ireland,</hi> to any perſon or perſons whatſoever, of any Lands, Tenements, or Hereditaments ſettled upon, or confirmed unto, or intend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to be ſettled upon, or confirmed unto Sir <hi>Theophilus Jones</hi> Knight, his Heirs and Aſſigns, by his Maieſties gracious De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration of the thirtieth of <hi>November,</hi> One thouſand ſix hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred and ſixty, recited in one Act of Parliament, intituled, <hi>An Act for the better execution of his Majeſties gracious De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration for the ſettlement of his Kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> and ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfaction of the ſeveral Intereſts of Adventurers, Souldiers, and other his Subjects there,</hi> ſhall be of any force or validity to hinder the ſaid Sir <hi>Theophilus Jones,</hi> his Heirs or Aſſigns, from inioy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the full benefit intended to the ſaid Sir <hi>Theophilus Jones,</hi> his Heirs and Aſſigns, by his Maieſties ſaid Declaration<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Any thing in the ſaid Act contained to the contrary thereof notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:32421:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 21 -->
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
